JASON WONG

(778)-929-7546 j.wong.9@alumni.ubc.ca jasonkcwong.com github.com/jason-wong-9

PROFILE

Striving to find the best solutions to complex problems in a pragmatic manner. Excellent oral and written communication skills gained from relevant customer service experiences. Self-challenger living by the values of embracing inevitable mistakes with integrity and positivity.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BRITISH COLUMBIA

Combined Major in Business and Computer Science Completion: 2018

SKILLS

PROFICIENT: Java, HTML/ CSS, Front-end JavaScript FAMILIAR: Swift, AngularJS, Node.js, Bootstrap LEARNING: C, C++, Android Ruby on Rails, Python

EXPERIENCE

IBOOKUNION BOOKSTORE

Vancouver, BC

Information Technology Executive

2015-current

- Formulated plans to improve user's experience with features that added clarity and increased accessibility on the webpage
- Updated the database to efficiently book information and past transactions to allow information to be instantaneously shared

FREE GEEK VANCOUVER

Vancouver, BC

Dismantle Volunteer

2013-2014

- Dismantled used computers and sorted reusable hardware to be rebuilt into low-cost computers for schools and community institution
- Resulting in an acquisition of better understanding in the basic procedures of rebuilding a computer with recycled items

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Moscrop Official iOS App

September 2015 - Current

- Displays daily student newsletters/bulletins along with the school's calendar and teachers' contacts
- Adopted Parse as a database to allow the iOS app to synchronize with the existing Android app
- Improved user experience by adding different themes to allow users to customize their personal app interface

MyCFL (SportsHack)

November 2015

- Allows football enthusiast to receive the latest feeds from CFL athletes' social medias
- Implemented cosine similarity to draw matches between users and athletes by comparing the athlete's physical attributes against user's provided information

Course Watcher

August 2015

- Serves the purpose of watching course availabilities on UBC SSC
- Incorporated external libraries to deliver email notifications to users
- Anticipate to develop this application further into a website, or iOS application

Mind The Gap (School Project)

August 2015

- Implemented JSON parsing to extract data from Transport For London API
- Integrated OsmDroid library to display train stations and the rail system on map

AWARDS

AP Scholar

College Board 2014

Honourable Distinction

Euclid Mathematic Contest 2011-2014

School Championship

Cayley Mathematic Contest 2012